# **Kishor Kumar Sridhar**

645 Squaw Creek Drive Unit 203, Ames, IA – 50010 | (515) 708-7091 |  $\underline{kishorkumarsridhar@gmail.com}$  |  $\underline{LinkedIn}$   $\underline{Portfolio}$ 

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduate student in Information Systems with 3+ years of industry experience in data analytics, data science, business intelligence, client/stakeholder engagement, project management and database management. Proven experience in statistical analysis, implementing ML algorithms, and presenting compelling dashboards to support evidence-based decision-makings.

#### EDUCATION

Master of Information Systems, Minor in Statistics (STEM), Iowa State University, GPA – 3.75/4 Nov. 2020 B.E. in Electrical and Electronics, Anna University, India, GPA – 7.58/10 May 2013

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming:** R – tidyverse, ggplot2, leaflet; Python - numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib, statsmodels; Git

**Databases:** MS – SQL Server, MySQL, MS-Access, Teradata **Analytics Tools:** Power BI, Tableau, R Shiny, MS – Excel, DOMO, QGIS

**Statistics:** ANOVA, Hypothesis testing, MLE, Time series forecasting, A/B testing

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow May 2020 – Aug. 2020

### Data Science for Public Good Fellowship, Ames, IA

- Led two Data Science projects to implement an end-to-end Data Science framework using statistical modeling and analyses
- Developed an R Shiny dashboard to improve public awareness of Iowa's resources related to mental and physical health, education, and childcare for evidence-based policy-making in substance abuse prevention, treatment, and recovery programs
- Acquired data through web-scraping, built data pipelines, assessed data governance, and spatially mapped county-level composite indicators of Social and Natural Assets related to upward economic mobility
- Performed data-wrangling using Tidyverse, Dplyr packages in R and utilized GoogleMaps API with R and QGIS to map the physical addresses to Latitude and Longitude co-ordinates
- Collaborated with the Substance Abuse Bureau of Iowa Department of Public Health (IDPH) to spatially map publicly available data using R Shiny dashboard reflecting formal and informal 'Systems of Care' across all 99 counties in Iowa
- Communicated analytical findings to non-technical audience using R Shiny dashboard for assessing community well-being in Iowa

Data Science Intern June 2018 – May 2020

### Iowa Department of Transportation, Ames, IA

- Implemented time series forecasting using FB Prophet model to estimate customer wait-times for Live display on DOT website
- Performed hypothesis testing, statistical modeling on pavement conditions and created Power BI dashboards to recommend insights
- Applied topic modeling (NLP) on 10,000 public feedbacks to identify factors governing highway maintenance
- Developed efficient SQL scripts for data cleansing, transformation and data modeling for ad-hoc analysis and reporting

Data Analyst Intern May 2018 – Aug. 2018

### Iowa State University, Ames, IA

- Conducted spend analysis within departments in MS-Excel to identify procurement gaps and story-lined the results to stakeholders
- Performed factor analysis, What-If analysis on purchase trends of departments facilitating savings in vendor contract renewals

Business Data Analyst Aug. 2016 – Oct. 2017

Torus, Chennai, India

- Automated insurance claims processing systems with integrated document management to reduce turn-around time by 30%
- Defined the scope of projects by translating requirements into Epics, User Stories and running Sprints with clear timeframes
- Assisted in planning, development, implementation of multivariate & A/B testing to improve conversion rate based on various KPIs

Programmer Analyst Feb. 2014 – July 2016

Infosys, Chennai, India

- Performed extensive data governance activities using Enablon EHS tool for a data migration project to modernize legacy systems
- Improved database performance by reducing query execution time by 50% using efficient SQL queries and stored procedures
- Communicated as a liaison between the client and technical team to deliver key business solutions using Agile methodologies
- Leveraged Microsoft SSIS to transform data for ETL processes; coordinated with QA teams to execute UAT cycles

#### **LEADERSHIP**